Guide to the English Department records, 1895-2006 RG0070
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
English Department records
1895-2006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Dept. of English
Moskowitz, Faye
McAleavey, David W.
Griffith, Patricia Browning
Clair, Maxine
Ziegler, Anna
Shore, Jane
Chandra, Vikram
Daiya, Kavita
Ihimaera, Witi Tame
Evaristo, Bernardine
RG0070
5.75 Linear Feet
This collection contains minutes of committee and departmental meetings, Tupper lectures, Ph.D. field exams, class mid-term exams, course descriptions, correspondence, CDs and DVDS, photographs of past faculty (1895-1976) and other materials pertaining to the English Department and the Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers. The collection is organized into three series, two containing department files and the third containing the records of the Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Engliish Department. The material related to the Jenny McKean Moore Fund were donated by Faye Moskowitz and Susan Willens in two separate accessions.
Gift of David McAleavey 7/29/2009 (acc. 2009.041)
Historical or Biographical Note
The English Department of The George Washington University is responsible for undergraduate English requirements and offers undergraduate and graduate degrees.
English and Literature have always been a part of the curriculum from Columbian College's founding in 1821 to the present. Requisites for admission in 1822 included an acquaintance with English grammar and arithmetic, a thorough knowledge of geography, and the ability to read and write Latin. The prospective student had to be able to translate, with a high degree of competence, Caesar's Commentaries, and the works of Virgil, Sallust, select orations of Cicero, and the New Testament in Greek. A candidate for advanced standing from another college had to pass examinations in all subjects previously taken and show that he left the other institution in good standing. No one was admitted without satisfactory credentials of good moral character.
Jenny McKean Moore (1923-1973) was a writer and social activist in Washington, D.C. After her passing in 1973, the Jenny McKean Moore Fund was established at the George Washington University. Formed in 1976 with an endowment left by Jenny McKean Moore, the purpose of the fund is to choose a candidate to teach four semester long creative writing workshops at George Washington University as the Jenny McKean Moore Writer-In-Residence.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains minutes of committee and departmental meetings, Tupper lectures, Ph.D. field exams, class mid-term exams, course descriptions, photographs of past faculty (1895-1976), and CDS and DVDs of courses taught by GW faculty as distance education courses in 2005. The collection covers 1895 to 2000. The collection was transfered to the University Archives by the Chair of the English Department in 1995.
The third series of this collection contains administration files, financial files, correspondence, clippings and other material pertaining to the Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers.
Collection Organization
Organized in four series: department files, department files, Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers records, and Distance Education course recordings.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Washington (D.C.); Creative writing; Distance education; Committees; Lectures and lecturing; Photographs; Examinations; George Washington University
- Departmental files, 1895-1987; RG0070 Series 1; 2 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is a collection of committee and departmental meetings, Tupper lectures, Ph.D. field exams, class mid-term exams, course descriptions, and photographs of past faculty (1895-1976). The materials range in date from 1964 to1987.
  - Tupper Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tupper Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tupper Fund--Computer printouts of account, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Committee Report, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Committee Report: Undergraduate Programs in literature, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committee Report: graduate renovation committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tupper--Anne R. Barton Lecture Manuscript, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sample MA and Ph.D. exams, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MA and Ph.D. reading lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum committee (Prof. Ganz, chairman), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Committee--graduate programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committee--Appointments, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Advisory Council, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advising, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - McCandlish Fellowship, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Shepard Memorial Fund, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bequests, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Tupper Fund--Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Language Examinations, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Graduate programs--English Department, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - President's Commission, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Washington and Writing, Spring conference, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Structure of the Department, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Curriculum Committee: Department of English, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Undergraduate Major Programs--English Department, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Advisor's Handbook, Department of English, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Course Descriptions, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fall 1985-Spring 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Graduate Program review--Report and Actions, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Graduate faculty correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - English 11 with Palmer Graham, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Departmental meeting, April 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Graduate Faculty, 05/01/1986 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - English Department, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Departmental meeting, 04/04/1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Development Office, J. Anderson, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Departmental meeting, November 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Meeting with Dean Lovitt, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Departmental meeting November 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Departmental meeting October 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Departmental meeting October 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Composition of the Department of English, meeting, September 13, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Departmental meeting, September 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Departmental meeting, 04/21/1986 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ad Hoc Committee: Composition and Part time faculty, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Tupper--Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "The Potomac" Literary Magazine, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ph.D. Field Exam--American Poetry, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D. Field Exam--American Romanticism, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Personnel--grants, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - English Majors, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Departmental Meetings, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Independent Study, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lectures, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Literary Society, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personnel (New Plan), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ph.D. Reading Guide: Old English, History, Middle English, Chaucer, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Prizes, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Undergraduate Programs, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Undergraduate Advisees, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Program, Graduate School, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - English Tutorial, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Composition, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Course Descriptions, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Review Committee (Ganz), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Departmental Memoranda, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - English for International Students, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - American CIV (Department), undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Agenda: tenure meeting, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Columbian College, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Tupper--Hallett Smith manuscript, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tupper Memorial Shakespeare Lecture, Robert B. Heilman, 03/1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Waith, Eugene, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Tupper--Harry Levine Lecture manuscript, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Tupper--Essays and correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Departmental meeting, 05/08/1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Departmental meeting, 04/07/1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Departmental meeting, 05/03/1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Departmental meeting, 02/02/1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Departmental meeting, 01/14/1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Departmental meeting, 11/05/1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Professors meeting, 10/22/1987-11/05/1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Professor Meeting, annual review (copies), 09/29/1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Departmental meeting, 09/03/1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Faculty meeting, March 24, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Professor Meeting, 03/10/1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Meeting with professors, 03/03/1987-03/12/1987 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Departmental meeting January 20, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Departmental meeting, 01/05/1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Tupper Fund--donors and mailing list information, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Tupper--David Bevington Lecture manuscript, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Ben DeMott, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Tupper--Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Lecture--preparations, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Donors, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Tupper--publications (and royalty records), undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Framed Photographs: English Department, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    General note
    Bement, Stone, Cole, Tupper, Shepard, Baker, Adams, Cooper, Bolwell, Smith
  - Framed Photographs: Anna Pearl Cooper, 1927-1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Framed Photographs: William Lewis Turner, 1941-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Framed Photographs: Milton Crane, 1964-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Framed Photographs: Charles William Cole, 1939-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Framed Photographs: Robert Whitney Bolwell, 1920-1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Framed Photographs: Edward Ronald Weismiller, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Framed Photographs: Robert Hamilton Moore, 1949-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Framed Photographs: Averett Howard, 1941-1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Framed Photographs: James Harold Coberly, 1945-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Framed Photographs: Ernest Sewall Shepard, 1926-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Framed Photographs: DeWitt Clinton Croissant, 1905-1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Framed Photographs: Courtland Darke Baker, 1924-1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Framed Photographs: William Allen Wilbur, 1895-1935 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Framed Photographs: Elizabeth Truman Wright, 1956-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Framed Photographs: Joseph Quincy Adams, 1934-1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Framed Photographs: Frederick Salisbury Tupper, 1936-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Negatives of photos in Lisner Hall 404; Faculty pictures fall 1978 (unframed) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Departmental meeting, 11/14/1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Departmental meeting, 10/17/1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Departmental meeting, 08/28/1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Professor meeting, 09/26/1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Professor meeting, 05/15/1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Composition, Fall 1984 and Spring 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Departmental meeting, 03/20/1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Departmental meeting February 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Departmental meeting, 01/17/1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Tenure Staff Meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Statements of departmental policies regarding full-time teaching appointments, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Program of Course, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Comm. On programs, English Department, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 90 Hour Program, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Composition Program, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Surveys--English, American, European, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - English Department Students correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Program of Courses, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Summer Academic Program, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Academic Program, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Department Constitution, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Ph.D. Field Exam: American Realism, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Ph.D. Field Exam: American Drama, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - English 9, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - English 11, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - English 91, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - English 92, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - English 101, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - English 102, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - English 103, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - English 105-106, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - English 107, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - English 108, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - English 111, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - English 112, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - English 115, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - English 116, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - English 117, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - English 118, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - English 120, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - English 121, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - English 122, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - English 123, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - English 125, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - English 126, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - English 127, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - English 128, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - English 129, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - English 130, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - English 131, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - English 132, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - English 133, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - English 134, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - English 135, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - English 136, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - English 137, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - English 138, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - English 145, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - English 151, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - English 153, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - English 154, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - English 155, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - English 156, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - English 157, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - English 158, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - English 161, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - English 162, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - English 163, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - English 164, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - English 165, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - English 166, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - English 167, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - English 168, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - English 170, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - English 171, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - English 172, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - English 173, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - English 174, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - English 175, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - English 176, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - English 177, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - English 178, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - English 181, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - English 194, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - English 219, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - English/French 271, midterm exams, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Departmental files, 1895-2000; RG0070 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains newsletters, correspondence, programs, lectures, syllabi, award winning student essays, and special projects. They range in date from 1933 to 2000.
  - Awards and Prizes De Witt Clinton Croissant Prize Essay, 1951-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - English Department, 1973-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - English Departments - Class Projects, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English Department - Kaleidoscope (Award Winning Student Essays), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - English Department - Special Events, 1977-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - English Department - Syllabus and Readings, 1930's, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - English Department - Tupper Lectures, 1963-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - English as a Foreign Language Department, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Jenny McKean Moore Fund for Writers records, 1978-2006; RG0070 Series 3; 3 Linear feet
  Jenny McKean Moore (1923-1973), a writer and social activist in Washingtons, D.C. Wife of Paul Moore, the 13th bishop of New York(1972-1989) and mother of nine children including poet Honor Moore. In 1968 she published a book, The People on Second Street, a memoir of her life with small children and an Episcopal priest husband in an urban parish in downtown Jersey City during the 1950's. Also in 1968, she served as the advance woman for Abigail McCarthy in the McCarthy campaign. She had also joined a feminist consciousness raising group in Cleveland Park. By 1972 she had published several feature articles in the Washington Post, was working on a play, and taking playwriting classes at George Washington University. After her passing in 1973 from liver cancer, the Jenny Mckean Moore Fund was established at George Washington University. The records found in boxes 10 through 12 were donated by Susan Willens on behalf of the family of James Heller. Mr. Heller served both as secretary and as the attorney for the Board of Directors of the Fund.
  The Jenny Mckean Moore Fund for Writers was formed in 1976 with an endowment left by Jenny Mckean Moore. The purpose of the fund is to choose a candidate to teach four semester long creative writing workshops at George Washington University as the Jenny McKean Moore Writer-In Washington.
  - Board of directors, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - By Laws, 04/04/1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Trust Fund drafts, proposals, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Budgets, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Budets for advertising, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Endowment gift information, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Report and questionnaire for workshop participants, 05/1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Report Tix for Kids, 04/10/1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reports, miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Meeting minutes, agendas, 1979-1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Contracts, agreements, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - List of candidates, 1977-2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lists of Poets, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Job lists, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Lists Literary Newspapers, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Literature Live proposals, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Announcements of fund, 1977-2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Press releases, 1976-2003 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda: creation of fund, 02/06/1975-02/22/1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Memoranda, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Memoranda, 1981-1995 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Memoranda, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: to Faye Moskowitz, 1974-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Eda Kriseova, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: contracts, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: contracts, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Recommendations of Writers in Residence, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Recommendations for Julia Alvarez, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Resumes of writers, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Work of Julia Alvarez, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Work of Lucille Clifton, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Work of Peter Meinke, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Work of LeRa Jones, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Works of Gloria Naylor, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Works of writers: miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Applications forms, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Application procedures, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Workshop materials: collected poems, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Workshop materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Readings programs, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Programs, brochures, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Programs: miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Flyers: Reading series, 1989-2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Flyers: workshop, 1998-2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Flyers, posters, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Flyers, posters, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Memoir: Jenny Moore, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Play: The Job, Jenny McKeen Moore, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Mariam Shapiro, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Posters: oversize, 1977-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Agreement forms, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Works of Jenny McKeen Moore, oversize, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - JMMF - GW Endowment, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jenny Moore Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Kampelman, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nations Bank Bank Statements, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Nations Bank Bank Statements, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - JMMF By laws, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jenny Moore - Board List, 1993-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Jenny Moore Fund for Writers, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Jenny Moore Fund - Asst Treasurer, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - JMMFW - DC Franchise Tax Exemption, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Income Tax Returns - Jenny McKean Moore Fund, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Income Tax Returns - JKMMF, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Income Tax Returns - JKMMF, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Income Tax Returns - JKMMF, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Jenny Moore Fund - Takes, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Jenny Moore Fund Bank Account, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - JMMF, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Jenny Moore Fund, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jenny Moore Fund, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jenny Moore Fund, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Young Peoples Workshop - Sample poems, 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Iona Senior Services, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "East of the River" DC Humanities Council, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 8)